Are you ready, kids?
孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
All: Aye, aye, Captain!
全体：是啊是啊，队长！
I can't hear you.
我听不到你说话。
All: Aye, aye, Captain!
全体：是啊是啊，队长！
♪ Ohh... ♪
♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
All: Spongebob Squarepants!
全部：海绵宝宝！
♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
All: Spongebob Squarepants!
全部：海绵宝宝！
♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
♪ 如果是航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
All: Spongebob Squarepants!
全部：海绵宝宝！
♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
-All: Spongebob Squarepants!
-Ready?
-全部：海绵宝宝！
-准备好？
All: Spongebob Squarepants!
全部：海绵宝宝！
Spongebob Squarepants!
海绵宝宝！
Spongebob
海绵宝宝
Squarepants!
方裤！
♪ ♪
Oh, Neptune,
哦，海王星，
surely this isn't the behavior
befitting a king,
这肯定不是行为
适合国王，
hiding in bed for days on end,
连续几天躲在床上，
doing nothing but watching
daytime television.
除了观看什么也不做
白天的电视。
Wait!
等待！
Rochelle was just about to meet
her biological parents.
罗谢尔正要见面
她的亲生父母。
Is this about
turning 5,000 today?
这是关于
今天就满 5000 岁了吗？
No.
不。
Oh, my darling Amphitrite,
哦，我亲爱的安菲特里忒，
it is not my age
that troubles me so.
这不是我的年龄
这让我很困扰。
It is that our son, Triton,
will not be able to share
这是我们的儿子特里顿，
将无法分享
in my revelry.
在我的狂欢中。
Let's forget about Triton
for just one day.
让我们忘记特里顿吧
就一天。
It's your 5,000th birthday,
for shell's sake.
今天是你的 5000 岁生日，
为了壳的缘故。
Okay.
好的。
So long as there's no one
careless enough
只要没有人
够粗心的
to mention Triton.
不得不提的是海卫一。
Order up, Squidward!
下令吧，章鱼哥！
I bet you're wondering why
I'm not using my hands today.
我打赌你想知道为什么
我今天没有用手。
Not in the least, Spongebob.
一点也不，海绵宝宝。
Okay, okay.
I'll tell you.
好吧，好吧。
我告诉你。
Your order, ma'am.
您的命令，女士。
I'm not using my hands
because today
我没有用我的手
因为今天
is work without your hands day.
是没有双手的工作日。
You should give it a whirl,
buddy.
你应该尝试一下，
伙计。
Krusty Krab,
Spongebob speaking.
蟹堡王,
海绵宝宝在说话。
Just a minute, please.
请稍等一下。
Mr. Krabs,
it's a Queen Amphitrite.
蟹老板先生，
这是安菲特里忒女王。
She wants to have King Neptune's
birthday party here.
她想要海王星国王的
生日聚会在这里。
Ooh, she does, does she?
哦，她愿意，是吗？
I'll handle this, laddie.
我会处理这件事，小伙子。
Yes, Queen Amphitrite.
是的，安菲特里忒女王。
Very convincing,
非常有说服力，
but you'll have to call
pretty early
但你必须打电话
很早
to fool old Eugene Krabs,
为了愚弄老尤金·克拉布斯，
prankster!
恶作剧者！
They think
I was born yesterday.
他们认为
我是昨天出生的。
Whoa!
哇！
Does 7:00 work for you,
your majesty?
7:00 适合你吗？
陛下？
Oil up your spatula, boy,
给你的抹刀加油，孩子，
for tonight,
you fry for a king!
今晚，
你为国王而煎炸！
So much for work without
your hands day, Squarepants.
工作就这么多，没有
你的双手日，方形裤。
You answer to a higher calling
this day.
你响应更高的召唤
这一天。
I have the capability!
我有这个能力！
Okay, that's enough, Patrick.
好吧，够了，帕特里克。
Thank you.
谢谢。
You two really outdid
yourselves.
你们两个真的很优秀
你们自己。
It almost makes me want
to pay you.
这几乎让我想要
付钱给你。
Oh, yeah.
哦，是的。
Looks like this area could use
a few more decorations.
看起来这个区域可以使用
还有一些装饰品。
Squidward!
章鱼哥！
Now what?
现在怎么办？
The decorations over here
look a little sparse.
这里的装饰品
看起来有点稀疏。
Why don't you hang up
a few balloons or something?
你为什么不挂断电话
几个气球什么的？
Oh, that's better.
哦，这样好多了。
Looks lovely, Squidward.
看起来很可爱，章鱼哥。
Excellent work.
佳作。
How goes it over here?
这里进展如何？
All set, Mr. K.
一切准备就绪，K 先生。
5,000 patties,
5,000个肉饼，
one for every year
Neptune's been alive.
每年一个
海王星还活着。
5,000 patties
5,000 个肉饼
at $3.99 a pop?
3.99 美元一支？
400...
Leave it to your old boss here
交给你的老老板吧
to capitalize
on such a momentous occasion.
大写
在如此重要的时刻。
Wow.
哇。
Why, you rolled out
the red carpet.
为什么，你推出了
红地毯。
This ain't for you lot!
这不适合你们！
This is for King Neptune.
这是给海王星国王的。
Today is his birthday.
今天是他的生日。
Oh, wait a minute.
哦，等一下。
King Neptune is coming here?
海王星王要来了？
Oh, I'm a huge fan
of the royal family.
哦，我是个超级粉丝
皇室家族的。
I just love
everything they do.
我就是爱
他们所做的一切。
Oh, could we please
maybe watch them eat?
哦，请问我们可以吗
也许看他们吃饭？
Right here,
through the window, you know?
就在这里，
透过窗户，你知道吗？
Don't be ridiculous.
别开玩笑了。
Why in Neptune's name
would I let you--
为什么以海王星的名义
我能让你——
See Neptune eat!
看海王星吃东西！
Only $5!
只需 5 美元！
Only a few seats left.
只剩下几个座位了。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Do you have change
for a twenty?
你有零钱吗
二十个？
Nope, sorry.
不，抱歉。
Guess it's $20 for you, then.
猜猜你的价格是 20 美元。
Don't be shy, folks.
别害羞，伙计们。
Seats are going fast.
座位抢得很快。
♪ ♪
Greetings,
my obedient flock.
问候，
我听话的羊群。
You were right, honey.
你是对的，亲爱的。
Hearing these mortals
cheer for me
听到这些凡人的声音
为我欢呼
has made me feel better already.
已经让我感觉好多了。
Excuse me,
Mr. Royal Sea King-ness.
对不起，
皇家海王先生。
Your table is this way, sir.
先生，您的桌子在这边。
These seats
are surprisingly comfortable
这些座位
出奇的舒适
for being no more
than primitive storage vessels.
因为不再存在
比原始的储存容器。
Oh, husband, I'm so glad
to see you're enjoying
哦，老公，我很高兴
看你很享受
your birthday party.
你的生日聚会。
And I am glad
that you're glad, my dear.
我很高兴
你很高兴，亲爱的。
And I'm glad that you're glad
that I'm glad, my King.
我很高兴你高兴
我很高兴，我的国王。
And I'm glad
that you're glad
我很高兴
你很高兴
that I'm glad
that you're glad that--
我很高兴
你很高兴——
All: All right already!
全体：已经好了！
And methinks
I shall continue to enjoy it
我认为
我会继续享受它
so long as there continues
to be no mention of the name--
只要继续存在
不提名字——
Triton?
海卫一？
Is there a Triton here?
这里有特里同吗？
Is there anybody missing
from this party
有没有人失踪
从这个聚会
that any of you guys can see?
你们中有人能看到吗？
Nope.
There's nobody missing.
没有。
没有人失踪。
We're all here.
我们都在这里。
Oh, I was sure
there's somebody--
哦，我确定
有一个人——
Oh!
哦！
Here it is right here.
就在这里。
An empty seat.
一个空座位。
That's not an empty seat.
那不是一个空座位。
My wife is sitting there.
我妻子坐在那里。
No, not that chair,
your highness.
不，不是那把椅子，
殿下。
That one.
See?
那个。
看？
It even has its pretty name card
that I made still on it.
它甚至还有漂亮的名片
我仍然在上面做的。
Oh, no.
哦，不。
T-R-I-T-O-N.
T-R-I-T-O-N。
You sure you don't know anyone
named Triton?
你确定你不认识任何人
名叫特里同？
Should I put it down
yes or no?
我应该把它放下吗
是还是不是？
Triton is our son.
特里同是我们的儿子。
But as you can see,
但正如你所看到的，
the king doesn't want
to talk about it right now.
国王不想要
现在就谈论它。
Thank you, my darling.
谢谢你，我亲爱的。
I'd rather not share
with this addled mortal
我宁愿不分享
和这个糊涂的凡人
the woeful story of our son,
Triton.
我们儿子的悲惨故事，
海卫一。
Oh, that's probably
a good thing.
哦，那大概是
一件好事。
Yeah, you don't want
to go there.
是的，你不想
去那里。
But I suppose
I could tell it.
但我想
我可以说出来。
No, no, no.
It's fine. It's fine.
不，不，不。
没关系。没关系。
No, you're right.
I won't tell it.
不，你是对的。
我不会告诉它。
Whew.
Good thing too.
呼。
也是好事。
Instead I'm going to show
this 16-millimeter movie
相反，我要展示
这部16毫米电影
I made about it.
我做了这件事。
-Oh.
-Oh, boy.
-哦。
-哦，男孩。
Could someone please
dim the lights?
有人可以吗
把灯调暗？
it all started one day
while giving Triton
这一切都是从某一天开始的
在给予海卫一的同时
his smiting lessons.
他的教训。
That's how you strike fear into
the hearts of your subjects.
这就是你如何让恐惧进入
你的臣民的心。
Now you try, son.
现在你试试吧，儿子。
Son?
儿子？
Triton was increasingly
fascinated
海卫一越来越
着迷的
with the miserable world
of the lowly mortals.
与悲惨的世界
属于卑微的凡人。
Dad, when are you gonna teach
me the ball and stick game?
爸爸，你什么时候上课？
我玩球棒游戏吗？
Never.
绝不。
Now, take hold of your trident
and practice your smiting, son.
现在，拿起你的三叉戟
儿子，练习你的击打。
I don't feel like smiting.
我不想打。
I want to play
the ball and stick game.
我想玩
球棒游戏。
Okay, son.
好吧，儿子。
You want to learn
the stick and ball game?
你想学习
棍子和球游戏？
Well, here's your first lesson.
好吧，这是你的第一课。
Batter up.
击打。
it looks like I just hit
a single.
看起来我刚刚打了
一个。
Let's see if you can get
a home run, son.
让我们看看你是否能得到
儿子，全垒打。
Leave me alone, Dad.
别管我了，爸爸。
What was happening
to my own flesh and blood?
发生了什么事
为了我自己的骨肉？
Over the next few millennia,
在接下来的几千年里，
my son grew not only in size
我的儿子不仅长大了
but in perplexing behavior.
但行为令人困惑。
What is going on in here?
这里发生了什么事？
Hey, Dad, check it out!
嘿，爸爸，看看吧！
I'm studying chemistry,
我是学化学的
and I've just created a cure
for all mortal diseases.
我刚刚发明了一种治疗方法
对于所有致命的疾病。
how many times
do I have to tell you?
多少次
我必须告诉你吗？
We are Gods!
我们是神！
We don't have diseases,
我们没有疾病，
nor do we care whether or not
the mortals contract them.
我们也不关心是否
凡人与他们签订契约。
Gosh!
天哪！
Try as I might,
尽我所能去尝试，
it was becoming
increasingly apparent
它正在成为
越来越明显
that we would not agree
on the ways of the world.
我们不会同意
关于世界的方式。
I knew I had no choice.
我知道我别无选择。
There was only one last resort.
只有最后一招了。
No, not that one.
不，不是那个。
The island in the sky.
天空中的岛屿。
Isn't that island
a miniature golf course?
那个岛不是吗
迷你高尔夫球场？
No!
不！
The one on the other side
of the river.
另一边的那个
河的。
You mean the juvenile
correction facility?
你说的是少年
矫正设施？
But that place
is for losers, man.
但那个地方
是为失败者准备的，伙计。
Uh-huh.
嗯嗯。
Okay, I'm standing in here.
好吧，我就站在这里。
Now what?
现在怎么办？
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
This is bogus.
这是假的。
I'm sealing you inside
this magical shrinking cage
我将你封印在里面
这个神奇的缩小笼子
until you learn
to embrace your destiny
直到你学会
去拥抱你的命运
as one of the gods.
作为众神之一。
No!
不！
You call that shrinking?
你管这叫收缩？
Well, it only shrinks 7%.
嗯，它只缩小了 7%。
Man,
that is just beyond bogus.
伙计，
这简直就是假的。
Perhaps in your eyes,
it is beyond bogus,
也许在你眼里，
它超越了虚假，
but it is the only way
you'll learn.
但这是唯一的方法
你会学到的。
Reflect on this
for 10,000 years.
反思这一点
一万年。
You can't do this, man.
你不能这样做，伙计。
I've got a life to live.
我还有生活要过。
I can't be stuck
in this cage, man!
我不能被困住
在这个笼子里，伙计！
God.
上帝。
I hate you, old man!
You hear me?
我恨你，老家伙！
你听到了吗？
I hate you!
我恨你！
Oh!
哦！
And that's that.
就是这样。
Huh?
啊？
Okay, who's ready
for a piping hot Krabby Patty?
好吧，谁准备好了
想要吃滚烫的蟹肉饼吗？
Would you like the first one,
your highness?
你想要第一个吗
殿下？
Recounting this sad tale
has upset me so much,
讲述这个悲伤的故事
让我非常心烦意乱，
I've lost my appetite.
我失去了胃口。
Take those sandwiches away.
把那些三明治拿走。
Can't you see
the king is upset?
你看不到吗
国王不高兴了？
It's okay.
没关系。
Let it out.
把它放出来。
This is a rip-off!
这是一个敲诈勒索！
I paid to watch high-class
royal dining action,
我付费观看高级节目
皇家用餐行动，
not listen to a boring
sob story.
不听无聊的
哭泣的故事。
Ooh, looks like things
may be picking up.
哦，看起来像东西
可能正在回升。
Royal violence!
皇室暴力！
Why have you not obeyed me,
mortal?
为什么你不听我的话，
凡人？
Begone!
走开！
So who's gonna pay
for these, then?
那么谁来付钱
对于这些，那么呢？
Zap!
噗！
If Neptune
doesn't cheer up soon,
如果海王星
还不快高兴起来
me business is ruined.
我的生意毁了。
Oh, no.
哦，不。
This is all my fault
because I mentioned...
这都是我的错
因为我提到...
Well, it wouldn't be the first
time you've ruined everything,
嗯，这不会是第一个
当你毁掉一切的时候
but the worst part
is those 5,000 Krabby Patties
但最糟糕的部分
就是那 5,000 个蟹黄饼
that will end up going rotten
in the hot sun.
那最终会腐烂
在烈日下。
Stop, Squidward!
Please stop!
停下来，章鱼哥！
请停下来！
Your descriptions
are too horrifying
您的描述
太恐怖了
for my delicate sensibilities.
为了我脆弱的情感。
I do have a way with words.
我确实有一套用词的方法。
Oh, how I miss my son!
哦，我多么想念我的儿子啊！
Hey, that's it!
嘿，就是这样！
I'll fix all this by reuniting
Neptune with his son.
我会通过重聚来解决这一切
海王星和他的儿子。
Thanks again,
Mr. Bus driver!
再次感谢，
公交车司机先生！
Now, all I've got to do is find
King Neptune's long-lost son.
现在我要做的就是找到
海王星国王失散多年的儿子。
Come on, Krabs.
Think! Think!
来吧，蟹蟹们。
思考！思考！
Ooh!
哦！
Whatever it is,
no.
不管是什么，
不。
Squidward,
you're a man of culture.
章鱼哥，
你是一个有文化的人。
Go on.
继续。
Well, these highfalutin types,
they--
嗯，这些高调的类型，
他们——
They might appreciate that,
don't you think?
他们可能会感激，
你不觉得吗？
Why don't you try
and razzle-dazzle 'em
你为什么不尝试一下
让他们眼花缭乱
with all your pizzazz?
与你所有的活力？
Pizzazz.
活力四射。
Hold on to your hats
and glasses, people,
抓紧你的帽子
还有眼镜、人、
because Squidward
the fantabulous has arrived.
因为章鱼哥
奇妙的事情已经到来。
Thank you, thank you.
谢谢，谢谢。
This next one,
I wrote myself.
这下一篇，
我自己写的。
I like to call it
Three Barnacles Are a Crowd
我喜欢这样称呼它
三只藤壶是一群
Unless They've Known Each Other
For a Really Long Time.
除非他们彼此认识
很长一段时间。
♪ ♪
Things just got lame again.
事情又变得蹩脚了。
Yeah, well, they better get
un-lame real quick,
是的，好吧，他们最好得到
很快就不再瘸了，
or I'm asking
for my money back.
或者我问
为了我的钱回来。
No refunds?
没有退款吗？
Well, I guess
we're stuck here, then.
嗯，我猜
那么我们就被困在这里了。
What the--
什么是——
I had the strangest dream
that I just got hit in the head
我做了一个最奇怪的梦
我的头刚刚被击中
with a tiny toenail clipping.
用一个小脚趾甲剪。
Oh!
哦！
Hey, I was right.
嘿，我是对的。
It is a tiny toenail clipping.
这是一个很小的脚趾甲剪。
Another one.
另一个。
Plus some rope.
加上一些绳子。
Hey, man.
What's the big idea?
嘿，伙计。
有什么大创意？
Who said that?
谁说的？
Show yourself!
展示你自己！
I'm warning you.
我警告你。
I know how to use these.
我知道如何使用这些。
Whah! Whah! Whah!
Whah!
哇！哇！哇！
哇！
I'm down here, man.
我在这儿，伙计。
Oh, hello,
little fellow.
哦，你好，
小家伙。
Maybe you can help me.
也许你可以帮助我。
'Cause if I don't
find Triton soon,
因为如果我不这样做
很快就能找到海卫一，
Mr. Krabs
is gonna be real upset,
蟹老板先生
真的会很沮丧
because he spent a lot of money
on party decorations.
因为他花了很多钱
在派对装饰品上。
Party decorations?
派对装饰品？
For what?
为了什么？
For King Neptune's birthday.
为了庆祝海王星国王的生日。
So it's my old man's
birthday.
所以这是我老人家的
生日。
Big deal.
有什么大不了的。
You mean
you're King Neptune's son?
你的意思是
你是海王星国王的儿子？
I am,
我是，
but he doesn't seem
to think so.
但他似乎并不
这么认为。
Well, he sure seemed upset
嗯，他看起来确实很沮丧
that you weren't
at his birthday party.
你不是
在他的生日聚会上。
Ha!
That's a real good one, man.
哈!
这真是一件好事，伙计。
Real funny.
真有趣。
well, thanks, but I was just--
好吧，谢谢，但我只是——
Do you think if that old goat
really cared,
你认为如果那只老山羊
真的很关心，
he'd have me sealed up here
in this magical cage
他会把我封印在这里
在这个神奇的牢笼里
with nothing to do all day
but trim my fingernails, man?
整天无所事事
但是修剪我的指甲吗，伙计？
You're right.
你说得对。
It just doesn't make
any sense.
它只是不让
任何意义。
You're telling me, man.
你在告诉我，伙计。
I mean, gods shouldn't have
to use nail clippers.
我的意思是，神不应该
使用指甲刀。
They should be able
to will their fingernails
他们应该能够
修剪指甲
to whatever length they want.
无论他们想要什么长度。
Man, you're just like
all the rest.
伙计，你就像
其余的一切。
Don't go.
别走。
What if I there was a way
to free you
如果我有办法怎么办
释放你
from this magical cage?
来自这个神奇的笼子？
Then you could come
to your father's birthday party
那么你可以来
去你父亲的生日聚会
and settle your differences.
并解决你们的分歧。
Then I'd ask you to brush
your teeth first, dude.
那我就请你刷
首先你的牙齿，伙计。
Pee-yew!
尿尿！
Sorry, I haven't had anything
to drink in a couple days.
抱歉，我什么都没有
几天后喝。
My throat's a little dry.
我的喉咙有点干。
This cage is only so big, man.
这个笼子就这么大，伙计。
I'm sorry.
对不起。
I'll stop talking.
I swear.
我就不说话了
我发誓。
Never mind.
没关系。
Just undo the lock.
只要解开锁就可以了。
Boy, this really does
look complicated.
男孩，这确实是
看起来很复杂。
Oh, I see.
我懂了。
I'll just slide this square
to the right.
我只需滑动这个方块
到右边。
This one goes up.
这个就涨了
This one over here.
这边这个。
And--no, wait.
还有——不，等等。
No.
不。
Man, that really is
a tough nut to crack.
伙计，这确实是
一个棘手的问题。
That lock was forged
by the gods!
那把锁是伪造的
天哪！
Not just any numbskull
can open it
不只是任何麻木的人
可以打开它
like it's some cheap bag
of potato chips
就像是一些便宜的包
薯片
they found in the street.
他们在街上发现的。
Cheap bag of potato chi--
便宜一袋土豆气--
Wait a minute!
等一下！
Which way to the nearest
phone booth?
去哪条路最近
电话亭？
There's one behind that rock
over there,
那块石头后面有一个
在那儿，
but I don't see what--
但我不明白是什么——
Hello,
Patrick?
你好，
帕特里克？
Hey! Hey!
嘿！嘿！
You'll never guess what I found
today in the street--
你永远猜不到我发现了什么
今天在街上——
Yeah, I'll hurry.
是的，我会快点。
Oh, Patrick, you made it.
哦，帕特里克，你成功了。
This is that magical lock
I was telling you about.
这就是那把神奇的锁
我正在告诉你有关。
Hmm.
唔。
Yeah, I tried it
for hours and hours,
是的，我尝试过
几个小时又几个小时，
but I just can't get it to--
但我就是做不到——
Open!
Wow, already?
打开！
哇，已经了吗？
Patrick, you know,
I'll never figure out
帕特里克，你知道，
我永远不会明白
how you're able to do those
so darn fast.
你如何能够做到这些
太快了。
It's easy.
这很容易。
I just peel the stickers
off the squares
我只是撕掉贴纸
远离方块
and put 'em down
where they're supposed to go.
并把它们放下
他们应该去的地方。
Amazing!
惊人的！
Well, now that this
silly old cage is open,
好吧，既然这个
愚蠢的旧笼子打开了，
what do you say
we go pay my old man a visit?
你说什么
我们去拜访我的老人吗？
Hate to keep him waiting
on his birthday.
讨厌让他等
在他生日那天。
Well, you guys coming
or what?
嗯，你们来了
或者什么？
Wow.
哇。
Are you gonna take us
for a ride?
你要带我们去吗
搭车？
A ride.
一趟。
That's a great idea.
这是个好主意。
Both: Oh!
两人：哦！
Hey, you guys don't mind
if I pull over here
嘿嘿，你们不介意吧
如果我把车停在这里
for a second, do you?
等一下，你呢？
Sure, Triton.
当然，特里同。
What do you need to do,
use the bathroom?
你需要做什么，
使用浴室吗？
No, to tell you
I don't need you anymore.
不，告诉你
我不再需要你了。
What an interesting man.
多么有趣的一个人啊。
Ready for a room temperature
Krabby Patty yet?
准备好室温
蟹蟹帕蒂还没来吗？
Nope.
没有。
Careful.
小心。
This is made of imported wood.
这是由进口木材制成的。
Imported all the way
from that junk pile out back.
全程进口
从后面的垃圾堆里。
Neptune's inconsolable.
海王星伤心欲绝。
Maybe if there was something
to distract him from his pain.
也许如果有什么
以分散他对痛苦的注意力。
Well, the only thing
that can usually do that
嗯，唯一的事情
通常可以做到这一点
is something that hurts more
than the original pain.
是更伤人的事
比原来的痛苦。
Great idea.
好主意。
Go play 'em another song.
去给他们再唱一首歌吧。
He's back.
他回来了。
Oh.
哦。
How...nice?
多么……好？
If it pleases the King,
如果国王高兴的话
I would like to perform a--
我想表演一个——
What the--
什么是——
Behold!
看哪！
What'd he say?
他说什么？
I think he wants us
to look out the-- Oh, my!
我想他想要我们
留意——哦，天哪！
That was incredible!
太不可思议了！
Yeah, definitely worth
the 5 bucks.
是的，绝对值得
5块钱。
Son?
儿子？
Son, I demand to know
the meaning
儿子，我想知道
意义
of this impudent imprisonment.
这种无礼的监禁。
Well, it turns out
you were right, old man.
好吧，事实证明
你是对的，老人。
Being trapped in that cage
all those years
被困在那个笼子里
那些年
with nowhere to go
but up in here
无处可去
但在这里
made me realize something.
让我意识到一些事情。
Dabbling in the world
of mere mortals
涉足世界
凡人的
is totally lame.
完全是蹩脚的。
And this is how you intend
to show it?
这就是你的意图
来展示它？
No, man.
不，伙计。
This is how!
就是这样！
By flying through the roof?
飞过屋顶？
That was Triton,
Neptune's son.
那是特里同，
海王星的儿子。
I thought he was
in reform school or something.
我以为他是
在改革学校什么的。
Hey, can I have an autograph?
嘿，我可以要个签名吗？
Sure, you can.
当然，你可以。
Nothing can stop me!
没有什么可以阻止我！
What's happened here?
这里发生了什么事？
Hello?
你好？
Where is everybody?
大家都在哪里？
Do you think maybe Triton
was in that cage for a reason?
你认为也许 Triton
被关在笼子里是有原因的吗？
It's still standing.
它仍然站着。
But look.
但你看。
That mail hasn't been
picked up today.
那封邮件还没有
今天捡到的。
You're right.
你说得对。
We'd better use
the secret entrance.
我们最好用
秘密入口。
Be very, very quiet.
保持非常非常安静。
Got you, pal.
明白你了，朋友。
What?
什么？
Please!
请！
I'll be ruined.
我会被毁掉的。
Don't worry, Mr. Krabs.
别担心，蟹老板。
No one was going
to pay for them anyway.
没有人去
无论如何都要付钱给他们。
Oh, this is terrible.
哦，这太可怕了。
Tell me about it.
告诉我吧。
I never get free food here.
我在这里从来没有得到过免费食物。
Son, hear my words.
儿子，听我的话。
I can understand if you want
如果你愿意的话我可以理解
to keep me locked up
in this cage and zap me,
把我锁起来
在这个笼子里并攻击我，
but see it in your heart
to release these others,
但在你心里看到它
释放这些其他人，
for they are innocent.
因为他们是无辜的。
Well, maybe not all of them.
好吧，也许不是全部。
Sorry, old man.
对不起，老头子。
You lost me
at the "hear my words" part.
你失去了我
在“听我的话”部分。
He's unstoppable.
他势不可挡。
Only as long as King Neptune
is locked up.
只要海王星国王
被锁定。
Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
你在想吗
我在想什么？
Yeah, triple goo-berry sundaes
tonight after we free 'em?
是的，三重浆果圣代
今晚我们释放他们之后？
No, but I like your idea
better!
不，但我喜欢你的想法
更好！
Make ready the disguise.
准备好伪装。
Okay. Now.
好的。现在。
No! Please!
不！请！
No more!
不再！
Quick, Patrick.
快点，帕特里克。
Unlock it before he sees us.
在他看到我们之前解锁它。
You got it.
你明白了。
Spongebob,
scooch back a little.
海绵宝宝，
向后退一点。
Excuse me.
打扰一下。
Okay, got it.
好的，明白了。
You better hurry it up,
Patrick.
你最好快点
帕特里克.
He's getting bored.
他越来越无聊了。
Don't rush me!
别催我！
Okay, got it!
好的，明白了！
Zap!
噗！
I was just kidding, man.
我只是开玩笑，伙计。
No.
No, please.
不。
不，请。
I never meant to--
我从来没想过——
Son, I have tried all my life
to be gentle,
儿子，我一生都在努力
要温柔，
but this time, you have--
但这一次，你——
Are you responsible
for all this destruction?
你有责任吗
为了这一切的破坏？
Don't send me back
别送我回来
I-I-I--
我-我-我--
The cage?
笼子？
Why, son,
you've just given me
为什么，儿子，
你刚刚给了我
the best
5,000th birthday present
最好的
5,000 岁生日礼物
I've ever received!
我曾经收到过！
You've finally learned
to use your god powers.
你终于学会了
使用你的神的力量。
Now I know that when my reign
comes to a close,
现在我知道当我统治时
即将结束，
I will have a worthy successor,
我将有一位称职的继任者，
and that's really all I could
ever hope for as a king...
这就是我所能做的一切
永远希望成为国王...
Come here, you.
过来吧，你。
Aw, Dad.
I love you, man.
噢，爸爸。
我爱你，伙计。
Huzzah!
好哇！
Yay!
耶！
Whoo-hoo!
Yeah!
呼呼！
是的！
Hurray!
Whoo!
欢呼！
呼！
Celebrate!
庆祝！
Now let's go home, son.
现在我们回家吧，儿子。
Toodle-oo!
嘟嘟哦！
Neptune and friends, wait!
海王星和朋友们，等等！
What about the party?
聚会呢？
What about me restaurant?
我的餐厅呢？
Ah, yes!
啊，是的！
Many thanks,
whoever you are!
非常感谢，
不管你是谁！
It was the best birthday
I could ever have hoped for,
这是最棒的生日
我本来可以希望，
and it's all because
of your little employee there.
这都是因为
你的小雇员在那里。
None of this would have happened
if it wasn't for his actions.
这一切都不会发生
如果不是他的行为。
Did you hear that?
你听到了吗？
Neptune said this
was all because of me.
海王星这样说
都是因为我。
Well, Spongebob, that's--
嗯，海绵宝宝，那是——
Did you hear that?
你听到了吗？
Neptune said this was all
because of that guy.
海王星说这就是全部
因为那个家伙。
He did, did he?
他做到了，是吗？
Uh, Spongebob?
呃，海绵宝宝？
Yes, Patrick?
是的，帕特里克？
Do you think right now
might be a good time
你现在认为
可能是个好时机
to go get those
triple goo-berry sundaes
去拿那些
三重粘浆果圣代
you were talking about?
你在说什么？
I think right now
might be an excellent time.
我想现在
也许是一段美好的时光。
♪ ♪